1977年，旅行者1号探测器发射升空，去探索外太阳系的秘密
In 1977, the Voyager 1 space probe was launched to study the outer solar system.
两枚旅行者号探测器成为人类航天史上运行时间最长的探测器
The two Voyager space probes have become the longest operating spacecrafts in spaceflight history.
41年后，旅行者1号距离地球190亿公里，速度每小时61000公里
41 years later, Voyager 1 is now 19 Billion kilometres from Earth and travelling at 61,000km/h.
虽然旅行者1号是至今离地球最远的人造物体
Despite Voyager 1 being the furthest man made object from Earth,
我们仍然能和它进行例行通讯
we are still able to communicate with the space probe on a regular basis.
但在我们联系不到它之前，它最远能到哪里？
But how far can it go before we can no longer communicate with it?
要回答这个问题，我们得知道它如何在210亿公里外接收并发送数据
To answer this, we need to know how Voyager 1 receives and transmits data from 21 Billion Kilometres away.
地球会以20千瓦的功率向旅行者号发送无线电信号
A 20 KiloWatt signal is transmitted from Earth to Voyager 1 using radio waves.
信号要经过近20小时才能到达探测器
It takes almost 20 hours for the signal to reach the space probe
探测器敏感的天线会接收到信号
where it’s sensitive antenna picks up the signal.
作为对比，火星车平均只要15分钟就能把信息传回地球
For comparison, it takes the rovers on Mars an average of just 15 minutes to send messages back to Earth.
而旅行者号把数据发回地球所用的信号功率有20瓦
Voyager starts sending data back to Earth using a 20 Watt signal.
信号在穿越茫茫太空的时候会不断衰减
As it travels through space, the signal strength weakens.
等到达地球，信号就已经相当微弱了
And by the time it reaches Earth, the signal is barely detectable.
想和这种距离的探测器通信
In order to communicate with objects that are this far away,
信号有多强已经不重要了
it doesn’t really matter how strong the signal is,
只要你的接收端足够的灵敏就行了
as long as you have a receiver that is sensitive enough to pick it up.
NASA使用的是均匀分布在地球的三组天线构成的深空网络(DSN)
NASA uses the Deep Space Network which consists of three Antenna complexes equally spaced around the Earth.
每一组天线包含70米天线外加多个34米天线
Each complex has a huge 70 metre antenna along with multiple 34 metre antennae
组合起来能接收到比我们平常调频广播信号弱数千倍的信号
which can be combined to pick up signals that are thousands of times weaker than your standard FM radio signal.
DSN每天会花几小时的时间接收来自旅行者1号的信号
The Deep Space Network spends several hours each day listening for faint signals from Voyager 1,
到目前为止，探测器仍然在与我们“交流”
and so far, it continues to talk back to us.
50年来，我们探测信号的技术有了长足的进步
Since our methods for detecting signals has improved drastically over the past 50 years,
所以还真不好说我们到底能和太空中多远的物体交流
there isn’t really a limit on how far we can communicate with objects in Space.
以现有科技，我们能和若干光年外的物体建立可靠通信
With our current technology, we could reliably communicate with objects that are many light years away from us,
只要我们的接收端足够灵敏精准来接收极其微弱的信号
as long as our receivers are sensitive and accurate enough to pick up the extremely weak signals.
随着旅行者号离我们越来越远，信号往返所需时间就越来越长
As Voyager travels further and further away from Earth it takes longer to send and receive signals.
信号强度也会逐渐减弱，数据率也跟着下降
The signal strength also gets weaker and data rates become slower
使得与探测器通信难度越来越大
making it harder and harder to communicate with the spacecraft.
旅行者1号的旅程还会无限进行下去
Voyager 1 will continue on it’s journey indefinitely,
虽然我们与它没有通信的限制
and although there is technically no limit to how far we can communicate,
但我们和它的通信也剩不了几年了
our communication with Voyager 1 only has a few years left.
因为旅行者1号是核电池动力的，它的电功率每天都在衰减
Since Voyager 1 is Nuclear powered, it’s electrical power weakens each day.
在1990年，为了节省功率
In 1990, in order to save power,
工程师在旅行者号拍完“暗淡蓝点”那张照片之后关闭了它的相机
engineers turned off the spacecraft’s camera after Voyager took the famous “Pale Blue Dot” image,
照片中的地球只是茫茫宇宙深色背景中的一个蓝色像素点
which showed Earth as a tiny blue pixel against the darkness of space.
今天，旅行者1号上11个科学仪器只有4个还在运转
Today, only 4 out of the 11 scientific instruments on Voyager 1 are still active.
这些仪器用于收集太阳系外围的电磁场、太阳风、宇宙射线等数据
These instruments are being used to collect data on magnetic fields, solar winds and cosmic rays outside of our solar system.
旅行者1号将在大约八年内彻底耗尽电能，再也无法保持仪器的运转
In around 8 years, Voyager 1 will completely run out of power and will no longer be able to keep it’s instruments going.
科学家会继续与探测器通信，收集它探测的重要信息
Scientists will continue to communicate with the space probe and receive the important information it gathers
直到它发送完最后一比特数据
until it eventually sends its last bit of data
然后永远淹没在浩瀚宇宙之中
and disappears silently into space, never to be heard from ever again.
尽管旅行者号太空探测器大限将至
So although the end is near for the Voyager space probes,
但它传奇的旅程与其教会我们的宝贵知识仍然让我们受益匪浅
we can appreciate the incredible journey they have been on and the valuable science they have taught us.
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎投币点赞收藏分享转发关注评论充电~
感谢观看本期Primal Space，感谢赞助者们对每个视频的帮助
Thank you to the Primal Space Patrons who help to write and research each video.
想资瓷的人可以去Patreon资瓷，地址在下方
If you'd like to contribute to Primal Space, please visit Patreon.com/PrimalSpace,
满50位赞助者后赠送土星五号乐高模型哦
where we will be doing a giveaway of a Saturn V Lego set once we reach 50 Patrons.
所以记得关注，一起讨论、学习一个太空姿势
So make sure you're subscribed, so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
感谢观看，下期见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.